<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>AMPed</title>
 <link href="http://ampblog.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://ampblog.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2015-09-21T16:17:57-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://ampblog.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>amarkpark</name>
   <email>amarkpark@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Buffer Overflow</title>
   <link href="http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/21/buffer-overflow/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/21/buffer-overflow</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s-media-cache-ak0.pinimg.com/474x/cc/1d/10/cc1d10f10629131cbe16645cfd2a240f.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life has been disrupting my study time a lot in the last week.  I finally got some uninterrupted time to power through a lot of lessons and assignments to get caught up yesterday.  About 8 hours in I was feeling a lot like that classic Far Side above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the intensity of some of my study sessions I worry about retention.  I promise myself I’ll go back and run through all these basics again to reinforce what I’m learning.  Time constraints may make that a difficult proposition.  But at least I am reinforcing what I learn as I encounter different concepts in different contexts and can thus build complex interconnections of neural pathways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In programming for a computer, simple and elegant are ideal.  Make things work in the least complex fashion and eliminate potential points of failure through conscious design and careful implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In programming a human brain the more ways you can find to build pointers to new knowledge the better it will stick.  Perhaps that’s why I write mental methods to describe processes I encounter in the  world.  And revisit them when I learn more about Ruby, refining and refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Number of wags?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;gets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;chomp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;to_i&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;tailwags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;side&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;right&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;times&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
	    &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;side&lt;/span&gt;
    	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;side&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;right&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    		&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;side&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;elsif&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;side&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    		&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;side&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;right&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tailwags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was watching water boil the other day, trying to picture the code I would write to describe the transformation of thermal to exothermic to kinetic energy that happens when water boils.  I don’t have that one yet, perhaps in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmm… now I’m relating this back to OOP and trying to decide if I should define a Class for Boil and define Methods for types of energy transformations and for the chemical process of breaking apart the H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O molecule within that Class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There we have it.  Interconnections.  Reinforcing each bit of new knowledge I gain about Ruby by connecting it back to other knowledge that is already in my brain.  Sometime this takes me off on tangents.  (Like when I use the word ‘tangents’ and then flash on writing a method to compute tangents to a circle, and a Method to circumnavigate a circle within a Class for Circle… which takes me back to my Logo days and “down turtle” as I program the computer to draw a circle.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
This trippy programming-of-yore flashback has been brought to you by the letter: ə
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See?  Buffer Overflow.  Perhaps it’s time for a reboot.  :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now back to our regularly scheduled programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~AMP&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Syntax and Context</title>
   <link href="http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/18/syntax-and-context/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/18/syntax-and-context</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow.  I can’t believe it’s been over a week since my last post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been finishing up a second Web App and working on the fundamentals of Object Oriented Programming, building a class for playing cards and a class for a deck of cards and making them play well together (pun fully intended.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night when I got home from playing DJ (note: I’m not a DJ, but sometimes I play one on the radio) I got back to the business of studying Ruby.  I wanted to at least read through my lesson/challenge for today so that I could let my brain crunch on it over night.  All hail unconscious cognition!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem was, when I was reading through one of several linked documents on Fun with Arrays I found a mildly confusing line of code using “«” to build a puts output.  Aroo?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning a new programming language is much like learning any communal human language.  Not only do you have to learn the vocabulary, you have to learn the proper sentence structure, syntax and punctuation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In programming languages that means learning lots of new operators and syntax.  Programmers prefer to be, let us say, &lt;em&gt;EFFICIENT&lt;/em&gt; by nature (some may call it a tendency towards laziness,) so there are also a lot of contextual shortcuts used in programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading code is very similar to reading pure Physics or pure Math: Comprised of symbolic notations and flagrant abuse of the greek alphabet, it can be intimidating to the uninitiated.  Learning to read code can sometimes be the equivalent of learning to read hieroglyphics.  If you are caught without your Rosetta Stone it can be confusing at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was certainly the position I found myself in as I was reading a blog post about 2D Arrays.  In it there was sample code using a puts statement with an each_index loop to walk through array values and output them to the screen with other characters and spaces to be organized in a meaningful way for the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with Arrays, the “«” operator is generally used to push a value on to an array.  It was clearly NOT being used to do that in the puts statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much searching and hair-pulling I found that in the context of Strings “«” is a concatenation symbol to append a value to the current string.  Granted I could see from the code and expected output that that was the &lt;em&gt;anticipated&lt;/em&gt; action of the symbol, but my journey to the supporting documentation led me a merry chase through the land of string-literals and Here Doc notation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RTFM right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if this was a case of me missing that left turn at Albuquerque or a case of contextual foul.  I DO know that multiple functions of the “«” operator are now well-cemented in my brain, specifically BECAUSE it was a point of contention for me that required special attention for clarification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m considering this detour as I would consider taking the scenic, tree-lined, hilly route on my Mean Streak… I’m out to enjoy the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~AMP&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Community</title>
   <link href="http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/10/community/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/10/community</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://momdipity.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/Vibe-Photo.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peers.  Tribe.  Peeps.  Pack.  Niche.  Whatever name is meaningful to you the takeaway is this:  It’s good to have Community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a brief but priceless interval consulting and conversing with the student community at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefirehoseproject.com/&quot;&gt;FHP&lt;/a&gt; this afternoon.  They were generously and eagerly helping me troubleshoot an App up on Heroku.  It was an amazing experience for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a rather self-sufficient sort.  Life-long caretaker personally and former Network Specialist/Sysadmin for 14½ years professionally.  I am USED to working without a net.  Having to figure stuff out for myself because there is nobody else to turn to.  That tends to be my Modus Operandi.  It’s my ground state.  My normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The half hour this afternoon where my fellow students and alumni acted as a sounding board for me was magic.  I don’t actually mean in the @chat instance scope per se, I mean in the $chat global or universal scope.  Today was inspirational, the hint of tomorrow++ was even more so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having folks to cooperatively collaborate with me, sharing of their knowledge and taking the time to toss ideas around with me was an immensely positive experience.  I can only hope this is what team development will be like.  I have always enjoyed brainstorming and group strategizing.  Everyone bringing their strengths to the table and building something grander than the sum of its parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a lot of time in the last few years contemplating the act of Finding Your Tribe. And while I can’t say I’m quite there just yet (my day-to-day life is still lacking in like-minded individuals) when it comes to being immersed in a supportive community and the power of that experience to help your dreams take flight I can say for certain that the experience is part of my current learning paradigm&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; with the Firehose Project.  And today that hit home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jpe-LKn-4gM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott talks about Community starting ~10:46.  But watch the whole thing, seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~AMP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; 1. Heh… Paradigm… also known as a &lt;b&gt;Model&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Learning By Failing</title>
   <link href="http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/07/learning-by-failing/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/07/learning-by-failing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m just starting my third week of The Firehose Project online bootcamp. Thus far it has been a roller-coaster ride for me.  Days of intensity, days of distraction and days of quiet persistence.  Moments of sheer delight, moments of sheer frustration.  I’ve done as much soul-searching as I have pouring over code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any new learning experience, I am often awed by the enormity of what I don’t know.  Perhaps that should read: I am often &lt;i&gt;overwhelmed&lt;/i&gt; by the enormity of what I don’t know.  Many-a-time I have no choice but to helplessly follow along where my lessons lead, trusting that some future chapter will shed light on what is not yet clear to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Good Code comes from experience, and often experience comes from bad Code.”&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I am learning a great deal from my errors, typos, and mistakes.  Clever parallel to life, that.  After sludging through a particularly nasty experience, a little wiser for the pain, I generally say “Well I’m not going to do THAT again!”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FHP is clever in their teaching style in that they intentionally write certain errors into the lessons.  The better to teach what NOT to do.  I enjoy spotting the errors ahead of time when I can, trying to determine how to avoid them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I read the objectives of each lesson I try to pinpoint what files I’ll have to edit, what methods I’ll have to add.  Given a new process, I try to apply what I learn early in the lesson to other parts of my current App before I am instructed to do so, to see if I grokk it well enough to run with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most days I do everything I can to AVOID asking for help.  &lt;i&gt; Note: this is a blessing and a curse.&lt;/i&gt;  I learn more by figuring out for myself why something doesn’t work than I would by being spoon-fed the answer. BUT…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The woods are lovely, dark and deep,. But I have promises to keep,. And miles to go before I sleep,. And miles to go before I sleep.”&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is always a new rabbit-hole to dive down here.  Always just one more detail to be hammered out before going back to the lesson.  I have to remind myself that I have a finite period for learning all FHP has to teach me and there is a point at which it will do me more harm than good to keep struggling on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-be-monsters&quot;&gt;Here be Monsters:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final thought for tonight… There is a REASON why uncharted waters held fictitious monsters.  The unknown can be a dark and frightening experience as you find your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are always frustrations.  (Monsters to fight.)  Trying to learn and understand it all at once can get you lost, overwhelmed.  Sometimes there is no help but to take a step back and disconnect for a bit.  As much happy fun brain-candy as there is learning to code, an hour or two of a thorough distraction is like a server reboot.  Laugh.  Let it go.  Pick it up tomorrow.  Clear out the buffers, start fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unconscious cognition happens when you are focused on something else.  You may see clearly after a good night’s sleep and a playful interlude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~AMP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;1. Shamlessly stolen from “Good judgment comes from experience, and often experience comes from bad judgment.” –Rita Mae Brown &lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;2. &lt;u&gt;Stopping by Woods on a Snowy Evening&lt;/u&gt; BY ROBERT FROST&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Glassy-eyed Stare</title>
   <link href="http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/05/glassy-eyed-stare/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/05/glassy-eyed-stare</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;v101&quot;&gt;v.1.0.1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for this morning was to do TWO things… change the colors of the titles and navdrawer, and change the format of the post date to YYYY.MM.DD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly v1.0.1 of this blog represented at least 2 hours of work.  2 hours I didn’t have to spend.  AND I need to figure out how to fix the title links that link to the individual post pages.  I think it’s the same problem that I was having with content placement and relative vs. absolute paths.  As though perhaps something isn’t right in the layout hierarchy or the site.baseurl variable.  Meh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent 12 hours coding and styling a Web App in my online Full-Stack bootcamp yesterday. I managed to make pagination function.  Then I looked at how many more chapters were left in the lesson for this particular App.  I had finished Chapter 3.  There are 13 total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To say I was a tad deflated was an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a student Google+ group where we share and interface.  There are several posts there that describe a learning/enthusiam curve graph.  For certain I have taken the nose-dive into the major slump of the curves.  I am trying to keep my enthusiasm up as I learn how much I have to learn.  Trying to convince myself it may some day be worth it in the end when I may possibly get a job doing Full-Stack development for a living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt; Note the conditional statements above. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep.  I’m having a hard time finding hope with two hands and a flashlight in my teeth right about now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time for a snack.  Maybe some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.girlgeniusonline.com/ggmain/strips/ggmain20071015.jpg&quot;&gt;Spark Roast&lt;/a&gt; and a good &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.girlgeniusonline.com/newreaders.php&quot;&gt;Comic&lt;/a&gt;.  Because once my stomach is appeased I’m going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefirehoseproject.com/&quot;&gt;DIVE&lt;/a&gt; BACK IN DAMN-IT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~AMP&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Epiphany</title>
   <link href="http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/02/epiphany/"/>
   <updated>2015-09-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://ampblog.github.io/2015/09/02/epiphany</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;#YouKnowYoureAWebDeveloperWhen&lt;/strong&gt; A quick static page accidentally becomes a multipage Bootstrapped site w/ header logo and content in ver 1.1
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;that-was-my-ah-ha-moment&quot;&gt;That was my “Ah Ha!” moment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been revising what should have been a simple static page with a few lines of text on it for &lt;em&gt;HOURS&lt;/em&gt;, happily diving down the rabbit hole in order to resolve a few issues I had and adding “just one more thing…” “just one more thing…” until my single simple HTML page had become a sleek multi-page app with a header and a child page and a logo and content all nicely arranged just so in Bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the day I was composing three different methods to describe a dog’s tail wagging in Ruby and I was thinking of boiling water in terms of a Ruby method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding is my heroine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel a lot like Remo Williams right about now:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0089901/&quot;&gt;“The Adventure Begins”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~AMP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;//me&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;thod&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;works&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Number of wags?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;gets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;chomp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;to_i&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;tailwags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;right&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tailwags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;method&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;works&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Number of wags?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;gets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;chomp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;to_i&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;tailwags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;right&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
			&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tailwags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;method&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;works&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Number of wags?&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;gets&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;chomp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;to_i&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;tailwags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;right&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
		&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tailwags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;wags&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
